<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
    <packageId>CarbineAction.ModFixes</packageId>
    <name>Mod Fixes Pack</name>
    <authors>
        <li>CarbineAction</li>
    </authors>
    <supportedVersions>
        <li>1.5</li>
    </supportedVersions>
    <modDependencies>
        <li>
            <packageId>brrainz.harmony</packageId>
            <displayName>Harmony</displayName>
            <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2009463077</steamWorkshopUrl>
            <downloadUrl>https://github.com/pardeike/HarmonyRimWorld/releases/latest</downloadUrl>
        </li>
    </modDependencies>
    <loadAfter>
        <li>brrainz.harmony</li>
        <li>nilchei.dynamicdiplomacycontinued</li>
        <li>m00nl1ght.GeologicalLandforms</li>
        <li>Woolstrand.RealRuins</li>
        <li>multilangcolorfultraits.pirateby</li>
        <li>skyarkhangel.hsk</li>
    </loadAfter>
    <description>A consolidated patch pack for large RimWorld mods. Each fix only activates if its target mod is loaded — safe to install even if you don't have all the patched mods. More fixes will be added over time.

CURRENT FIXES:

--- Dynamic Diplomacy (Continued) ---

- Terrain validation: rejects battle tiles and conquest targets on problematic terrain. Retries with better tiles before giving up. Works alongside Geological Landforms. Rejects:
  - Impassable mountains (vanilla mountain tiles)
  - Extreme cliffs from Geological Landforms
  - Cave topology
  - Ocean/water-covered tiles
  - Extreme temperature biomes (below -20°C or above 50°C) — covers Alpha Biomes, HMC Biomes, Vile's Biomes, etc. where pawns can't survive long enough to resolve a battle

- Shambler/infection deadlock: when pawns switch factions mid-battle (e.g., get infected and become shamblers), they're now cleaned from the battle faction lists so DD's win check works correctly. Prevents battle maps from staying open forever.

- Hard timeout failsafe: if a battle runs past 7 game days without ending, force it to end via DD's timeout mechanism.

- HSK-tuned event rates: reduces DD event frequency from vanilla pace (3-5 conquests per 60 days) to HSK pace (1-2 conquests per 90 days). Matches the slower HSK progression curve. Per-event changes:
  - NPC_Conquest: 3-5 per 60d with 0.5d spacing → 1-2 per 90d with 20d spacing
  - NPC_DiploChange: 2-4 per 60d with 5d spacing → 1-2 per 60d with 15d spacing
  - NPC_Expansion: 1-2 per 60d with 15d spacing → 1 per 90d with 30d spacing
  - NPC_Convert: 1-2 per 120d with 30d spacing → 1 per 180d with 60d spacing

--- Geological Landforms ---

- Shared terrain utility used by DD fixes. Checks tile topology (CliffAllSides, CliffValley, etc.) to avoid problematic battle maps.

--- Real Ruins ---

NEW MOD FIX: Real Ruins
- World-tile relocation: POI icons moved off Mountainous/Impassable tiles via 10-ring BFS search for a valid neighbor. No more Factory/Military Base/Camp icons stuck in mountains.
- Local-map Scatter relocation: ruin blueprints that would overlap thick-roof rock / natural stone are relocated to cleaner cells on the map (30-candidate search). Covers all 13 POI types, background scatter, medium/large/POI gen steps.
- Effect: every Real Ruins icon on your world map is reachable from the map edge without having to mine through a mountain.

HSK-style tuning (auto-applied when both Real Ruins AND HSK are loaded — more hostiles, harder to get stuff):
- hostileChance: 10% → 35% (ruins are actual threats, not free loot stops)
- trapChance: 0.1% → 0.4% (4x more traps)
- forceMultiplier: 1.0 → 1.5 (hostile forces 50% stronger)
- scavengingMultiplier: 1.0 → 1.75 (most valuable items stripped before you arrive)
- itemCostLimit: 1000 → 400 silver (no premium loot)
- ruinsCostCap: 1 billion → 300k silver (no jackpot mega-bases)
- abandonedLocations: 20% → 50% (more truly abandoned POIs)
- deteriorationMultiplier: left at 0.0 — integrity falloff already damages edges naturally; double-penalty would make leftovers useless

Tuning only activates if HSK is detected. Non-HSK modpacks keep Real Ruins vanilla defaults.

--- MultiLang Colorful Traits ---

NEW MOD FIX: MultiLang Colorful Traits auto-extend
- MultiLang Colorful Traits colors traits by QUALITY (Unique / Good / Neutral / Bad / Terrible) using hand-curated XML lists for Core, HSK, RJW, AlienRaces, and CE. Any trait not on those lists stays uncolored — and its own "Dump" workflow requires manual XML editing per mod.
- This fix runs after MultiLang, inspects every TraitDef in the modlist, skips degrees MultiLang already colored (manual classification always wins), and auto-classifies the rest into MultiLang's 5 tiers using an identical color palette so everything looks visually consistent.
- Classification is mechanical: it scores each degree from skillGains, statOffsets/Factors, the parent TraitDef's disabledWorkTypes/Tags, random/forced mental states, hunger rate, pain modifiers, and required work tags.
- 8-tier classification using all the colors defined in MultiLang's ColorBase.xml:
  * Legendary (score &gt;= +7): pure bright green #00FF00 — exceptional positive
  * Good (+3 to +6): muted green #9AB973 — solid positive
  * Neutral (-2 to +2): plain white (label left untouched — reduces visual noise so only meaningful traits stand out)
  * Bad (-3 to -4): salmon orange #FF9966 — noticeable downside
  * Terrible (-5 to -6): red #ED2939 — serious downside
  * Nightmare (&lt;= -7): pure red #FF0000 — worst of the worst
  * Unique (strongly flavored mechanic, e.g. large psychic sensitivity swing): blue #0000FF
  * Restrictive (disables work types/tags, or has required work tags): purple #9370DB — shape-defining trait regardless of score
- Restrictive and Unique take priority over the score-based tiers so build-shaping and quirk mechanics are always visible at a glance.
- Log example: [Mod Fixes Pack] MultiLang: auto-classified traits (Good:60, Neutral:55, Bad:40, Terrible:20, Unique:10, skipped 185 already-colored).

Net effect: before the fix, ~30% of HSK modpack traits are colored (MultiLang's hard-coded lists). After, ~100% of traits are colored. MultiLang's hand-tuning is preserved on traits it knows; we just fill the gaps.

Auto-disables if MultiLang Colorful Traits isn't loaded.

COMPATIBILITY:
- All fixes are conditional — inactive if the target mod isn't loaded
- Zero overhead if a mod is missing
- Safe to install on any save
- Works with HSK (Hardcore SK) and vanilla

All logs are prefixed with [Mod Fixes Pack] for easy filtering in the debug console.
    </description>
</ModMetaData>
