<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
    <packageId>CarbineAction.ModFixes</packageId>
    <name>[CarbineAction] Mod Fixes Pack</name>
    <authors>
        <li>CarbineAction</li>
    </authors>
    <supportedVersions>
        <li>1.5</li>
    </supportedVersions>
    <modDependencies>
        <li>
            <packageId>brrainz.harmony</packageId>
            <displayName>Harmony</displayName>
            <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2009463077</steamWorkshopUrl>
            <downloadUrl>https://github.com/pardeike/HarmonyRimWorld/releases/latest</downloadUrl>
        </li>
    </modDependencies>
    <loadAfter>
        <li>brrainz.harmony</li>
        <li>nilchei.dynamicdiplomacycontinued</li>
        <li>m00nl1ght.GeologicalLandforms</li>
        <li>skyarkhangel.hsk</li>
    </loadAfter>
    <description>A consolidated patch pack for large RimWorld mods. Each fix only activates if its target mod is loaded — safe to install even if you don't have all the patched mods. More fixes will be added over time.

CURRENT FIXES:

--- Dynamic Diplomacy (Continued) ---

- Terrain validation: rejects battle tiles and conquest targets on problematic terrain (impassable mountains, extreme cliffs, caves, ocean). Retries with better tiles before giving up. Works alongside Geological Landforms.

- Shambler/infection deadlock: when pawns switch factions mid-battle (e.g., get infected and become shamblers), they're now cleaned from the battle faction lists so DD's win check works correctly. Prevents battle maps from staying open forever.

- Hard timeout failsafe: if a battle runs past 7 game days without ending, force it to end via DD's timeout mechanism.

--- Geological Landforms ---

- Shared terrain utility used by DD fixes. Checks tile topology (CliffAllSides, CliffValley, etc.) to avoid problematic battle maps.

COMPATIBILITY:
- All fixes are conditional — inactive if the target mod isn't loaded
- Zero overhead if a mod is missing
- Safe to install on any save
- Works with HSK (Hardcore SK) and vanilla

All logs are prefixed with [CarbineAction Mod Fixes] for easy filtering in the debug console.
    </description>
</ModMetaData>
